americanselect.org 2011-12-10

# Americans Elect 2012 | Privacy

We know your privacy is important to you, and we want you to know that it is important to us too. We created this Privacy Policy to explain the types of information we collect through AmericansElect.org, how we will use and protect this information once it is collected, and how you can opt-out of some of our uses of your information. We encourage you to review this Policy to make sure you understand how any personal information you provide us will be used.

[](https://privacy-policy.truste.com/click-with-confidence/ctv/en/www.americanselect.org/seal_s "Validate TRUSTe privacy certification")Americans Elect has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at Americans Elect. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will let you know by posting the changed Privacy Policy on this page. In some cases, for example, if we make any significant changes, we may contact you directly about them, such as by sending you an e-mail. Any changes will be effective immediately upon posting to AmericansElect.org.

  1. ### What information do we collect on AmericansElect.org?

We collect two general types of information from AmericansElect.org users: (1) non-personal information concerning the use of AmericansElect.org and (2) personal information that identifies or can be used to identify or contact an individual.

Non-Personal Information: As is the case with many Web sites, our servers automatically collect your browser type and IP address when you visit AmericansElect.org. We may also capture certain clickstream data, which includes, for example, the referring page that linked you to AmericansElect.org, the pages you visit on AmericansElect.org, the next Web site you visit when you leave AmericansElect.org, and any search terms you have entered on AmericansElect.org or a referral site.

In addition, we and our third party partners acting on our behalf may use cookies and/or pixel tags to keep track of your visits, preferences and profile information. Cookies are small data files stored on your computer’s hard drive at the request of a website, and do not contain personal information about you. Cookies may be used to enhance your experience on AmericansElect.org (including by allowing you to remain logged in); to store some of your preferences; or to collect general usage and aggregated statistical information that does not by itself identify you personally. To learn more about the use of cookies, including how to manage or delete them, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/learn_more.asp). Local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, may also be stored on your hard drive using a media player installed on your computer or device. Flash cookies operate a lot like other cookies, but cannot be managed in the same way as non-Flash cookies. For more information on Flash cookies, [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).

Personal Information: Most of the Personal Information we collect is what you provide to us. For example, you provide such information when you register for an account on AmericansElect.org, sign up to receive our newsletters, make donations, participate in a forum, survey and contests, or communicate with us by e-mail. The types of Personal Information we collect include, for example, name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, text message or SMS address, and certain demographic information. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. We collect credit/debit card information on our site. Any credit or debit card information you submit in your order to make a donation at AmericansElect.org is collected by a third party donation processor, Piryx, who will use this information only to immediately process your donation. We do not retain any credit or debit card information.

Information Obtained from Third Parties: In some instances, we may supplement the information collected from you with information that is received or otherwise obtained from third parties.

Personal Information about Children: AmericansElect.org is designed for registered voters who are at least 18 years old. We do not knowingly collect personal information from persons under 13. If you feel that we have unknowingly collected information from someone under the age of 13, please contact us immediately and this information will be removed.

#### Customer Videos

We post user videos on our web site, which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the user consent prior to posting the video.

We collect user feedback on our web site, which may contain personally identifiable information. We use your personal information only as necessary to provide this service to you.

  2. ### How do we use your information?

We and our trusted partners acting on our behalf may use the information we collect from and about you to:

    * process your donations
    * administer or develop the AmericansElect.org site and your account with us
    * respond to your requests, questions, and concerns
    * send you communications, including information about products, services, and events (offered by us and others) that we think might interest you
    * protect our rights and property

We and our partners may also use your information to help us assess the level of interest in AmericansElect.org, our e-mails, and our other messaging campaigns.

  3. ### Sharing with Third Parties

We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may share your personal information with third parties for a variety of reasons. In addition to sharing your personal information with third parties who provide services to us, we may share your information:

    * with third parties responsible for checking your information against voter registration databases
    * as required by law and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or those of third parties, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or comply with a court order or other legal process
    * in connection with a corporate change including a merger, acquisition or sale of assets.

In addition, we may share aggregate AmericansElect.org usage information that does not identify individual users with third parties for any reason, including, for example, marketing or analytical purposes.

  4. ### Security

We work hard to protect the security and integrity of Personal Information from the moment you begin to enter it on AmericansElect.org to when it is stored on our servers. For example, we use a secure socket layer (SSL) on pages where you create a profile and limit access to Personal Information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need it in order to do their jobs.

In addition to our security measures, you can also take steps to maximize your security online and to protect your Personal Information. Doing things like installing anti-virus software on your computer and keeping it up to date, not disclosing your password to anyone, and using encryption to secure your wireless networks at home will help ensure the security and confidentiality of your Personal Information. For more information about how to protect yourself online, visit [OnguardOnline.gov](http://www.onguardonline.gov/). 

#### Invite a Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to invite a friend to our site, we will ask you for your friend’s email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Americans Elect stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at info@americanselect.org to request that we remove this information from our database.

  5. ### Links to Third-Party Web Sites

AmericansElect.org may contain links, banners, widgets or advertisements that lead to other Web sites. We are not responsible for these other sites, and so their posted privacy policies will govern the collection and use of your information on them. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site visited after leaving AmericansElect.org to learn about how your information is treated.

  6. ### Consent to Processing

AmericansElect.org and this Privacy Policy are intended for users located in the United States. By registering on AmericansElect.org, you consent to the transmission to, and collection and processing of your information in the United States, and any other jurisdiction, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

  7. ### Your Access Rights

You may be able to manage or delete your preferences, profile, and other information by visiting a “my account” area (or similar area, if any) on AmericansElect.org. You may also inform us of any changes by contacting us at [info@AmericansElect.org](mailto:info@americanselect.org). We will endeavor to respond to your request promptly. Before we are able to assist you, however, we may require you to verify your identity or provide other details to help us respond to your request.

**Data Retention:** We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or deemed appropriate. If you wish to cancel your account, or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [info@AmericansElect.org](mailto:info@americanselect.org). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

  8. ### Opt Out

You have the right to tell us not to send certain communications to you. For example, you may tell us not to send you our promotional e-mails by clicking on the appropriate link included with any such e-mail you receive from us, or opt out of our SMS messages by texting STOP to the sending address. Please note, however, that even if you opt out of receiving promotional correspondence from us, we may still contact you in connection with your relationship, activities, transactions and communications with us, which are not promotional. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account, as outlined above.

  9. ### Contact Us

We welcome your questions and comments about privacy. Please feel free to contact us by e-mail at [info@AmericansElect.org](mailto:info@americanselect.org).
